（鳥のさえずり）
（室戸(むろと) 菫(すみれ)のあくび）
Sensei, are you listening?
（里見(さとみ)蓮太郎(れんたろう)）
先生 聞いてんのかよ？
Sorry. I was thinking about what
to make for dinner tonight.
ああ すまん
今晩のおかず
何 作ろうか考えていた
Wait a sec.
待てよ
話してみろって言うから
相談したんだろ
I was telling you about this
because you told me to!
The discrimination against the
Cursed Children in the Tokyo Area...
東京エリアに はびこる
呪われた子供たちへの差別…
And your concerns about how your lives are
going to be, now that Enju-chan's identity
そして 昨日 延珠(えんじゅ)ちゃんの出自が
学校にバレたことによる―
has been revealed at her school...
今後の生活への不安…
Your problems are so normal,
they're rather boring.
君の悩みは あまりに普通すぎて
つまらんのだよ
So you were listening!
聞いてんじゃねえか！
（菫）そもそも
人類は どうして―
Why does humanity have to
exterminate Gastrea, anyway?
ガストレアを
せん滅しなければならない？
Because it's the enemy of humanity.
人類の敵だからだ
But there are religious sects that
believe Gastrea is a messenger of God
世界では ガストレアを
地球を浄化するために現れた
神の使いだと
神聖視している宗教団体もある
that has come to cleanse the world.
As they see it, humanity is responsible for using up
彼らに言わせれば
人類こそが 資源を食い尽くして
地球をダメにする要因だ
all the world's resources, and destroying it.
That's just an extreme point of view
regarding humanity as unnecessary.
それは 最終的に
人類は不要だっていう極論だろ！
Besides, if Gastrea is a messenger of God,
そもそも
ガストレアが神の使いなら
what does that make the Cursed Children?
呪われた子供たちは
なんだっていうんだ！
（菫）フッ…
Agents of God serving as messengers
between humanity and Gastrea.
人類とガストレアとの
メッセンジャーを務める―
神の代理人
Enju is a human!
（蓮太郎）延珠は人間だ！
She is a human being with
a personality and a will!
１つの人格と意志をそなえた
人間だ！
決して それ以上でも
それ以下でもねえ！
She is nothing more and nothing less!
Exactly. See? You do understand.
そのとおり 分かってるじゃないか
あ…
Listen, Rentaro-kun.
（菫）なあ 蓮太郎くん
At least you know who you are
and where you came from.
君は 自分がどこの誰か
知っているだけ まだいい
Enju-chan doesn't even
know that about herself...
延珠ちゃんは
それすらも知らない
（蓮太郎）あ…
Most of the Cursed Children in the
outer district were abandoned children.
外周区の呪われた子供たちは
ほとんど捨て子だ
They never know their parents
or anything of the outside world,
彼女たちは 親も外の世界も
知らないまま―
and are only viewed with scorn by most.
多くの人間から
軽蔑のまなざしで見られる
So who's going support,
teach, and lead those girls?
そんな彼女たちを支え
教え導いてやれるのは 誰だ？
あ…
君たちは 家族じゃないのか？
Aren't you two family?
Thanks, Sensei.
先生 ありがとう
（菫）あっ そうだ
Oh, yeah...
I've got a message from your patron.
君のパトロンから伝言だ
He says to visit the student
council office once in a while.
たまには 生徒会室に
遊びに来いとさ
フッ…
（携帯電話の着信音）
Hello?
もしもし
Is this Satomi-san?
（担任）里見さんですか？
はい
Yes.
I'm Aihara-san's homeroom teacher. Um...
（担任）藍原(あいはら)さんの担任です
あの…
Aihara-san came to school this morning...
藍原さんが
今朝から登校してまして…
I'll be right there!
（蓮太郎）すぐ 行きます！
♪～
～♪
#03 The Children of Fate
（蓮太郎）
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（少年）学校 来んなよ！
（少女）ダマしてたんだ
Stop coming here!
You tricked us!
Don't come near me!
（少女）そばに来ないで！
（少年）帰れよ！
Go home!
You stupid Gastrea!
（少年）ガストレアめ！
Thanks to you guys killing anyone
and everyone, my family was...
お前らが 所構わず
殺しまくったせいで
俺んちは…
That wasn't me! I am human!
（藍原延珠）それは 妾(わらわ)じゃない！
妾は人間だ！ あ…
I am...
妾は…
あ… 妾は…
I am... human!
人間だ！
あ…
Rentaro...
蓮太郎
Enju,
（蓮太郎）延珠
let's change schools.
学校を移ろう
I do not... want to... give in.
妾は…
負けたく… ない
I made... so many friends...
友達も たくさんできたのに…
They aren't your friends anymore.
もう 友達じゃない
Even so...
それでも…
Even so, do we still have to fight?
それでも 妾たちは
戦わなければならないのか？
（ヘリのローター音）
Yes.
そうだ
Satomi-kun! We've located the Gastrea
that was the source of infection.
（天童(てんどう)木更(きさら)）里見くん
感染源ガストレアの潜伏先が
分かったわ！
We're going to get there first!
うちが一番乗りよ！
Did you really have to call Dr. Heli?
だからって ドクターヘリを…
I used up next year's tuition,
（木更）来年分の学費
使い込んじゃったから―
so if anyone beats us to it,
I'll have to quit school!
よそに取られたら
私 中退よ？
（蓮太郎）ん…
What is that?
あれは なんでしょうか？
（蓮太郎）ん？
It's a Gastrea!
ガストレアだ！
There are spiders that use webs
as parachutes and travel around.
巣をパラシュート状に編んで
旅をするクモがいるが―
It's sort of like that...
それと似たような原理で…
I see...
そうか これが
先生の言っていた―
This is one of the original abilities
that Sensei was talking about?
オリジナルの能力ってやつか
（後部ドアが開く音）
Enju?
（蓮太郎）延珠！
Enju, wait!
待て 延珠！
（ガストレアの悲鳴）
はっ… 高度を下げろ！
Decrease altitude!
Huh?
（操縦士）えっ？
（蓮太郎）早く！
Hurry!
G-Got it.
は… はい！
（蓮太郎）うっ うっ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Enju!
延珠！
（延珠）うっ
（ガストレアの悲鳴）
（延珠）うわー！
Enju!
延珠！
Rentaro... I defeated it.
蓮太郎 倒したぞ…
I have defeated it.
妾が倒したぞ
Well?
どうだ 妾は戦っただろう？
I fought it, didn't I?
Yeah...
ああ
I protected... everyone in school...
学校のみんな…
守ったぞ
Rentaro!
蓮太郎ー！
（延珠の泣き声）
You have me.
俺がいる
（延珠）えっ？
It may be true that all we
can do right now is fight.
（蓮太郎）確かに 今は
戦うしかないかもしれねえ
And I know how anxious you feel,
being unsure which way to go.
どこに向かえばいいか―
不安に思う気持ちも分かる
だがな！
But, Enju, you have me!
延珠 お前には俺がいる！
I care about you more than anyone else does!
お前を大切に思う気持ちは
誰にも負けねえ！
Even if the world doesn't accept you,
もしも 世界が
お前を受け入れなくても
I'll always be right by your side!
俺は いつでも
お前のそばにいる！
あ…
うん
Thank you, Rentaro.
ありがとう 蓮太郎！
All right. Let's get what we
came here for and go home.
さあ とっとと回収して
うちに帰ろう
Yeah.
（延珠）うん
I wonder what's in there.
（蓮太郎）何が入ってんだろうな
The Inheritance of the Seven Stars, huh?
七星の遺産か
I've got a bad feeling...
イヤな予感がする
Well done, Satomi-kun.
（蛭子(ひるこ)影胤(かげたね)）
ご苦労だったね 里見くん
（蓮太郎）うわっ！ うっ…
Rentaro!
蓮太郎！ あっ
Found you, Enju.
（蛭子小比奈(こひな)）延珠 見ーつけた
（延珠）うっ…
Tendo Martial Arts First Style, Number 8:
天童式戦闘術 一の型八番！
Homura Kasen!
焔火扇(ほむらかせん)！
（蓮太郎）ううっ
（影胤）フフフフ…
（銃声）
（蓮太郎）うわっ
うっ うっ…
I'll show you a move of my own.
（影胤）１つ 君に
私の技を見せてあげよう
Maximum Pain.
マキシマムペイン
（指を鳴らす音）
（蓮太郎）うわっ！
うわっ…
ぐっ… うわっ
ハァ…
Oh? You're still alive?
（影胤）
ほう まだ生きているか
ハァ… ハァ…
Enju... Run!
延珠 逃げろー！
あ… イヤだ！
No!
あっ
Rentaro!
蓮太郎！
ハァ ハァ…
あ… うっ…
Wait right there, Rentaro!
待ってろ 蓮太郎ー！
Papa! Enju ran away! I want to cut her!
パパ！ 延珠 逃げた！
斬りたい！
No, daughter of mine.
（影胤）ダメだよ 我が娘よ
If they join with other civil
officers, it'll be a nuisance.
ほかの民警と合流されたら
面倒なことになる
Let us finish our job here.
仕事を済ませよう
（刀を刺す音）
うっ
You're so weak... You're so weak!
弱いくせに！ 弱いくせに！
うわあ！
ううっ！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Any final words, my dying friend?
（影胤）何か言い残すことは？
死にゆく友よ
ハァ…
Go...
地獄に…
to hell...
落ちろ
Goodnight.
（影胤）グッドナイト
ああっ…
You are Satomi Rentaro-kun, yes?
（菫）里見蓮太郎くんだね
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
There's a choice I'd like you to make.
君に 選んでほしいことがあるんだ
Oh, Kisara-san...
あ… 木更さん
Welcome back, Satomi-kun.
（木更）おかえりなさい 里見くん
How long have I been asleep?
俺 どのくらい寝てた？
One day and about three hours.
（木更）丸１日と３時間くらい
They said your heart
君の心臓 手術の最後の最後で
動きだしたって
started beating toward the
very end of the surgery.
You didn't give up on living.
生きることを諦めなかったの
Well done.
偉いわ
The government has given us some information.
政府側から 情報が伝えられたわ
The case that Kagetane took contains
影胤が持ち去った ケースの中身は
a catalyst capable of
summoning a Stage Five Gastrea.
ガストレアのステージⅤを
呼び出すことができる
触媒だそうよ
Stage Five?!
ステージⅤ!?
You mean, of the eleven that
almost destroyed the world?
それって 世界を滅ぼした11体の？
Starting from Stage One,
ステージⅠから始まり
Ⅱ Ⅲと成長し―
Gastrea grows to Stage Two and Three,
then completes itself at Stage Four.
Ⅳで完成するガストレア
The Stage Fives exist outside of that evolution.
その進化の枠外に存在する
ステージⅤ
They've existed since the
appearance of Gastrea ten years ago.
10年前の
ガストレア誕生時からいて―
They're larger than other Gastrea,
どのガストレアより巨大で―
and Varanium magnetic fields
have no effect on them.
バラニウムの磁場に
一切 影響を受けない存在
Monoliths have been destroyed in various areas
ステージⅤによって―
いくつかのエリアで
モノリスが壊されたことがある
by these Stage Fives.
And the hordes of Gastrea that
infiltrate afterwards bring about
雪崩を打って侵入してくる―
ほかのガストレアたちが
引き起こすものは―
extinction.
大絶滅
Hiruko Kagetane has escaped the Monolith
barrier into the Unexplored Territory,
蛭子影胤は
今 モノリスの外
未踏査領域に逃げ
and has begun preparations
for summoning the Stage Five.
ステージⅤを呼び寄せる準備に
入っている
The government is about to launch
an extensive pursuit operation.
まもなく 政府主導で
大々的な追撃作戦が発動されるわ
And if that doesn't stop them,
the Tokyo Area will be...
それで ヤツらを止められなければ
東京エリアは…
You're planning to go? Can you win?
行く気なの？ 勝てるの？
I have to win!
勝てなきゃ ダメなんだ！
You're going to die.
死ぬわよ
I'm prepared for that.
覚悟のうえだ！
フゥ…
あ？
You're supposed to be resting, you know.
（木更）
君 絶対安静なのよ 本当は
Sorry, Kisara-san.
悪い 木更さん 俺は…
I...
There's someone else you should
be apologizing to before me.
私の前に 謝る相手がいるでしょ？
えっ？
あっ 延珠!?
Enju?
Shh!
シーッ
When did she...
（蓮太郎）いつの間に…
Ever since you were brought in here.
（木更）あなたが
ここに運び込まれてから ずっと…
Rentaro... you imbecile...
蓮太郎 アホ…
Man... I really am useless.
ああ…
俺 ホント ダメダメだな
I made you worry, Enju...
心配かけたな 延珠
I'm sorry.
ごめん
（携帯電話の着信音）
Yes.
はい
For you.
（木更）あなたによ
（蓮太郎）えっ？
It's Seitenshi-sama.
（木更）聖天子(せいてんし)様から
（蓮太郎）あ…
Satomi-san, we will be initiating an
operation to pursue Hiruko Kagetane.
（聖天子）里見さん
蛭子影胤 追撃作戦が始まります
I would like you to participate in this operation.
私は あなたに この作戦に
参加してほしいと思っています
Why me?
（蓮太郎）どうして 俺なんだ？
You should know that better than anyone else,
（聖天子）それは―
あなたが一番
分かっているはずですよ
Satomi-san.
里見さん
Just remember that I'm not doing this for you guys.
（蓮太郎）あんたらのために
やるわけじゃないことを―
忘れんな
I wish you luck, Satomi-san.
（聖天子）ご武運を 里見さん
あっ 先生
Sensei?
From your patron.
君のパトロンからだよ
It's perfect.
完璧だ
Thank him with the reward.
礼は 手柄をあげて返してやれ
This is a farewell gift from me.
これは 私からのせん別だ
AGV experimental drugs.
ＡＧＶ試験薬
If you can avoid it, don't use them.
できれば 使うなよ
While I was unconscious, I had a dream
意識がなくなってるときにさ
of when you operated on me ten years ago.
10年前 先生に
執刀される夢を見たよ
What I did to you can never be
forgiven, no matter what I say.
私が君にやったことは
どんな言葉を尽くしても
許されることではないだろう
I've never once resented you since that day.
俺は あの日から
一度だって 先生のことを
恨んだことなんてない
（ドアが開く音）
I order you as the President...
社長として命令します
フッ
Crush the Kagetane and Kohina pair and
影胤 小比奈ペアを撃破して
stop them from summoning the Stage Five.
ステージⅤ召喚を止めなさい！
Give me a hundred times more
effort than you have in the past,
君は 私のために
今までの100倍 働いて！
and I'll give you a thousand times back.
私は 君の1000倍働くから！
I will stop them, no matter what.
絶対 止めてみせます
あなたのためにも
For your sake, as well.
（木更）うん
あっ
（足音）
（物音）
（延珠）あっ
（雄たけび）
ハァ… 危ねえ
That was close...
（爆発音）
（２人）あっ
Damn it! Some pair is using explosives.
バカ野郎
どこかのペアが
爆発物を使ったな
（２人）うわっ
Rentaro... What is that?
蓮太郎
あれは なんだ？
（蓮太郎）あっ
That's...
あれは！
（雄たけび）
A Stage Four?!
ステージⅣ！
（延珠･蓮太郎）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Enju!
（蓮太郎）延珠！
（延珠）うりゃー！
（延珠）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（蓮太郎）ハァ… 延珠？
Enju?
イヒヒッ
Don't move.
動くな！ あっ
You're...
お前は…
Wait! Enju!
待て 延珠！
She's not an enemy.
（延珠）あ…
（蓮太郎）こいつは敵じゃねえ
えっ？
Do you remember me?
お前 俺のことを覚えてるか？
Of course.
（千寿(せんじゅ)夏世(かよ)）もちろんです
Just a moment!
（延珠）待て待て
妾は こんな女 知らないぞ
I do not know this woman!
Explain what this is about!
どういう関係か説明しろ！
She's the partner of a Promoter named
Ikuma Shogen. She's an Initiator.
（蓮太郎）
こいつは 伊熊将監(いくましょうげん)っていう―
プロモーターの相棒
イニシエーターだ
I'm Senju Kayo.
千寿夏世です
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
（延珠）フンッ
I will not accept such a woman.
妾は あんな女 認めないからな
For crying out loud...
（蓮太郎）ったく
I only asked her to keep watch outside.
外で見張りしてろって
言っただけで
Why did she get so moody?
なんで あんな不機嫌になんだよ
I believe the reason is clear as day.
理由は 明白なように思えますが
えっ？
Am I strange to you?
不思議ですか？ 私が
Um, well...
ああ… いや
I'm an Initiator with the model of a dolphin.
私は イルカの因子を持つ
イニシエーター
I just have a higher IQ and
better memory than most.
通常より 知能指数と
記憶能力が高いだけです
You're the smart one,
yet you're the rear guard
（蓮太郎）
頭脳派のお前が後衛で―
and Shogen is the vanguard?
将監が前衛なのか？
That's a pretty unusual style.
珍しいスタイルだな
Shogen-san is all muscle,
right down to his brain.
（夏世）将監さんは脳みそまで
筋肉で出来ているうえ―
On top of that, he's just
too stingy to do backup.
バックアップなんて
みみっちいことが―
できないだけです
Let me see your gun.
お前の銃 見せてくれ
What if I refuse?
イヤだと言ったら？
That's fine, if you feel
nothing about being saved.
かまわねえぜ
お前が助けられたことを
何も感じてないならな
I have learned one thing.
１つ 学びました
Once you expect something in
return, your good deed fails.
見返りを求めた時点で
善行は堕落しますね
Why did you use explosives in the forest?
どうして 森で爆発物を使った？
A trap...
ワナに…
We could see a pattern of
flashing lights deep in the forest.
森の奥で点滅する
ライトパターンが見えましてね
We thought they were fellow
civil officers and went closer...
民警だと思って
近づいていったんです
And it was a Gastrea.
（蓮太郎）
それが ガストレアだった
Without thinking, I used a high-explosive shell.
とっさに 榴弾(りゅうだん)を
使ってしまいました
And then we were attacked by
the Gastrea in the forest,
それで 森のガストレアに襲われて
and I was separated from Shogen-san.
将監さんと
はぐれてしまっているわけです
Did the Gastrea inject any fluid into you?
（蓮太郎）ガストレアに
体液を注入されたのか？
The fluid it injected was a very small amount,
注入された体液は
ごく少量でしたので
so there is no increase in the corrosion rate.
侵食率の上昇はありません
There is no need to worry about
me turning into a Gastrea.
私が ガストレア化する心配は
ありませんよ
Listen. Make sure you get
checked out once we get back.
いいか？ 戻ったら
ちゃんと検査しておけよ
You are worried about me?
私を心配しているんですか？
Something wrong with that?
（蓮太郎）悪いか？
I'm a little envious of Enju-san.
私 少しだけ
延珠さんが羨ましいです
She has never killed anyone before, has she?
延珠さんは おそらく
人を殺したことがありませんね
I can tell by looking at her eyes.
目を見れば 分かります
And you have?
（蓮太郎）お前は あんのか？
Indeed. Even on our way here,
I killed another pair that we met.
（夏世）ええ
ここに来る途中も―
出会ったペアを殺しました
Why would you do that?!
どうして そんなことを？
Because Shogen-san ordered me to.
（夏世）将監さんの命令です
He said he wouldn't let anyone have the reward
仮面野郎をぶち殺す手柄は
誰にも渡さないと…
for killing the guy in the mask.
I was scared...
怖かったです
My hands shook, but that was all.
手が震えました
でも それだけです
I believe I'll get used to it soon.
じき慣れると思います
Don't give me that shit!
（蓮太郎）ふざけんじゃねえ！
（夏世）えっ？
The scariest thing about killing
people is getting used to it!
殺人の一番怖いところは
慣れることだ！
When you kill someone and realize
you won't be punished...
人を殺し 自分が
罰せられないと知ったとき―
That's when people forget
all about punishment!
人は 罪の意識を忘れていく！
Are you able to say that because
you've killed someone before?
それは あなたが
人を殺したことがあるから
言えるんですか？
はっ…
You have very mysterious eyes, Satomi-san.
（夏世）里見さんは
不思議な瞳をしていますね
I'm sure you have a complicated past.
きっと 複雑な過去を
お持ちなのでしょう
You're so kind, yet you
have such a scary face.
優しいのに… とても怖い顔
Why am I
俺…
trying to talk like I know everything?
何 偉そうなこと言ってんだろうな
Sorry about that...
Forget what I just said.
悪い　今の忘れてくれ
Why are you apologizing?
（蓮太郎）あっ
（夏世）どうして 謝るんです！
What you're saying is right.
里見さんの言っていることは
正しいのに
You are right...
あなたは正しい…
There's... something wrong with me now.
私… 今 変です
I can immediately come up with various
arguments to what you just said,
里見さんに対する反論なら
即座に何十個も思いつくのに
and yet I don't want to deny your words.
里見さんの言ってくれたこと
否定したくない
I've never... felt like this before.
この気持ち…
初めてです
You...
お前…
（無線のノイズ音）
Hey! If you're alive, reply!
（伊熊将監）おい！
生きてんだったら返事しろ！
I'm glad you're safe, Shogen-san.
ご無事で何よりです 将監さん
Kayo, I have great news!
（将監）夏世 いいニュースがある
I found the bastard in the mask!
仮面野郎を見つけたぜ！
はっ…
So you're really going?
（蓮太郎）やっぱり 行くのか？
Despite how he is, he is my partner.
（夏世）あんな人でも
私のパートナーなので
What about you, Satomi-san?
里見さんは？
Other than you two, there are
ten pairs attacking, right?
（蓮太郎）将監以外に
10組以上のペアが―
攻めてるんだろ？
I'll at least see how the fight ends.
戦いの結末だけでも 見届けるさ
Do you know what that is, Satomi-san?
里見さん
あれが何か ご存じですか？
The Stairway to Heaven?
（蓮太郎）天(あま)の梯子(はしご)か
It is an example of a mass murder weapon.
（夏世）殺りく兵器の代表です
A symbol of the Stolen Generation's hatred...
“奪われた世代”の憎悪の象徴
The current generation...
今の時代は…
Is what's going on right now really
a wholesome attempt at revival?
今 行われているのは
本当に 健全な
復興なんでしょうか
That's where Kagetane is...
あそこに 影胤が…
♪～
～♪
#04 Black Bullet
Rentaro...
（延珠）蓮太郎…
Rentaro's the only one
who can save the world.
蓮太郎だけが 世界を救える
No one else but Rentaro...
ほかの誰でもない 蓮太郎だけが…